nusextra.co.uk 2017-10-05

# Privacy Policy: www.nus.org.uk

Thanks for following our link to find out more about what we are doing to look after your personal information.

NUS Services is part of the National Union of Students. NUS is one of the oldest and probably most trusted student organisations in the world, and we work hard every day to help to make your experience as a student the best it can be. We influence national and local policies in areas that are important to you, such as accommodation, fees and the right to study. We also run ground breaking programmes to drive change, such as improving environmental impact and reducing alcohol abuse.

We know that when you pass your personal details to us, you are trusting us to keep them safe, and we will do everything within our power to do this. We cannot promise to don capes and red underpants and turn into super-heroes, but we promise to do everything in our power to protect your data so that no villains can get access to it.

To offer you some incredible deals we do share your information with other companies, but we are very careful who we accept as partners. For an organisation to be an official partner they must prove that they have the best interests of you in mind, and that they are honest and ethical. Only if they pass these integrity checks will we share your information, and even then, only if you give us permission in the first place. You can also ask us to stop sharing your information at any time. We believe in transparency and further on we have listed the partners we currently work with.

We want you to feel confident knowing that when you pass your details on to us they will be safe and protected. If we have not made anything crystal clear, or you would like to know anything else, just get in touch, we will be happy to answer any questions you may have.

We will collect personal information about you, including your personal details, your course details, tastes and preferences. We do this by capturing the information you give us, by analysis of traffic on the website, and by cookies.

## Cookies

Cookies are a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser. When you first visit our website you will be given the opportunity to allow or disallow cookies; cookies are a great mechanism to allow you to get the very best interactivity from our website. On revisiting our website we may recognise the cookie, giving us information about your last visit. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance.

Some cookies are essential for our website to work, and others voluntary. We use cookies for recognition purposes at logon through the use of a persistent cookies placed on your hard drive, and standard cookies to track activity around the site. This standard cookie is deleted at the end of each session/visit. We may also use cookies to track any click-through from promotional emails sent by NUS/NUS Services Ltd and/or our selected partners.

I would like to stress that NUS.org.uk does not use cookies to obtain any personally identifiable information from yourself. The cookies used by NUS.org are required for site functionality. You are able to block or restrict the cookies set by NUS.org from within your browser settings, however doing so may affect the site functionality although you may still use most of the features of the website.

Visit our cookie page to find out more about the cookies used on NUS.org.uk; if you wish to find out further information about cookies you can obtain additional details from [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). This site offers a comprehensive guide on cookies and how to remove them from your computer.

I have already mentioned that we use analytics tools to understand how people use our website. When a visitor uses our website [www.nus.org.uk](http://www.nus.org.uk/) we use Google Analytics to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns.

Google allows us to understand things like the number of visitors we are getting and which parts of the site they are visiting. Unless you specifically log in with your user details, at no time will we identify you personally whilst travelling through the site. If you would like to know more about these demographic and interest reports from Google you can discover more about them here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2700409?hl=en>

This analytical information is processed in a way which does not identify anyone and we promise we will never share your identity with any third parties, including Google.

From time to time and only where appropriate we may provide anonymous aggregate statistical information about our services, competitions, clients, traffic patterns and other site information to third parties, but again I would stress that these statistics will not include any information that could identify you personally.

On our website search terms are captured anonymously for analysis purposes.

We use information collected about you to help us (a) develop the design and layout of the website to ensure that it is as useful and enjoyable as possible and (b) provide the products and services which interest you. Sometimes this information may also be used by us and our associated companies to inform you about changes to the website, new services and products or offers that you might find interesting. If you do not wish to receive this information, you can simply use the 'Unsubscribe' function at any time.

At any time you have a right to ask us what information we hold about you. You can also, if you wish, obtain a copy of this information, all you have to do is ask. We will just need to check your identity and may make a small charge to cover the cost of the enquiry.

We have a plan in place to ensure that the information we hold on you is regularly reviewed and kept accurate and up-to-date. If it becomes apparent that the information we hold on you is inaccurate or factually wrong, we will correct it as swiftly as possible. You have a right to ask us to stop processing your details at any time as long it does not affect any contract agreement in place.

International Travel. ISIC [www.isic.org](http://www.isic.org/) For those fortunate and intrepid members travelling the world, the ISIC Card is a great opportunity. If you sign up for the ISIC card we will pass on your name and your assigned card number to ISIC to facilitate the processing of your card, and to send you details of offers to make your trips memorable.

Food Savings. If you, like me, love food, then being a member of the Gourmet Society [www.gourmetsociety.co.uk](http://www.gourmetsociety.co.uk/) is terrific. If you sign up for the Gourmet Society Card, we will pass on your card number, card expiry date and number of years valid, your name, email, students' union and mobile phone number to them to facilitate the processing of your card. Knowing where you live, and what you like, the Gourmet Society will send you details of convenient local eateries and great offers - we all know that food tastes even better when you get wonderfully tasty food but at significant discounts.

General Emails. You will receive emails from us advising you of deals and offers which we believe will be of value to you, and this will include offers from a wide range of companies and organisations. We have not passed your details on to these companies, but have been asked to send the email on their behalf. If you wish to take up the offer you will contact them directly. We always include an unsubscribe option on every email and we will stop sending these if you change your mind in the future.

In addition, there are two partners with whom we currently share your contact data. These are carefully selected, vetted and chosen to offer real value and benefits to you. We also ensure that they adhere to the same Data Protection standards that we do. You have the right to withdraw your permission at any time.

Insurance Quotations. Our Partner Endsleigh ([www.endsleigh.co.uk](http://www.endsleigh.co.uk/)) uses your personal information to ensure they have the best rates to offer you if you contact them directly, and to check that the information you supply is accurate. We also give you the option to opt in to Endsleigh’s great product offers and services when you sign up for your NUS extra card. We supply Endsleigh with the following data: Your name, gender, country, date of birth, email, Students Union, start and end date of study, course, course level and prospecting source.

Job Opportunities. Graduate Prospects [www.prospects.ac.uk](http://www.prospects.ac.uk/) Job opportunities and career advice. Prospects understand your career journey better than anyone - you can find them on every university campus, working in partnership with the NUS and careers services to bring you the very best opportunities. As well as providing graduate jobs, internships and postgraduate courses, the site has careers advice written by specialist professional advisers and a range of tailored tools such as Prospects Planner, which match your skills and interests with the best career options for you.

We share your contact information, including course details, with them so that they can match you with the perfect opportunity. They will also contact you directly with opportunities and information. We supply Graduate Prospects with the following: Your - name, gender, email address, country, students union, course and level, year of course, study start and end date, date of joining.

Finally, from time to time we may identify new partners who can make a difference to your student experience.

If you would like more information on what information we share, then please do not hesitate to get in touch [enquiries@nusextra.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@nusextra.co.uk)

Of course, there are certain situations when we have no choice but to pass on your information, for example if asked by the police investigating a crime, but we will only do so when legally obliged to do so. There are other occasions when we may share your personal information, such as, for example, to third parties investigating the misuse of our NUS Extra Card, or our website.

When you entrust your personal information to us we take as much care of it as if it were our own. NUS spend a lot of time, money and resources on ensuring that the personal details you entrust to us are protected from loss, misuse and abuse. We constantly monitor our infrastructure for vulnerabilities and ensure that all IT systems, patches and anti-virus software are up-to-date.

Your information is stored on secure servers based within the EU and we have some pretty impressive physical and electronic security to keep it safe and sound. We also take regular encrypted backups in case of a problem.

The safety of your data is very important to us and we train our key staff in Data Protection to ensure that they both understand, and comply, with their obligations under the Act. We carefully control who has access to your information, and ensure that it is only used in the way you would expect.

I hope that you now appreciate that when you pass your personal details to us we will keep them safe, secure and only use them in a way that you would expect. The NUS is fully committed to its members, and our reputation for honesty, integrity and transparency is reflected throughout our privacy policy.

If you have any comments, suggestions or feedback, be that positive or constructive regarding how we are using your personal data, if you believe the information we hold on you is out-of-date or you would like to unsubscribe from our mailing list, please contact our Marketing Director by email on [enquiries@nusextra.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@nusextra.co.uk) or by writing to us at the address below.

NUS SERVCIES LIMITED  
Ian King House, Snape Road  
Macclesfield, Cheshire  
SK10 2NZ

[www.nus.org.uk](http://www.nus.org.uk/) is operated by the National Union of Students, based in London.
